上一集我们进行了第一次网络挑战，我们首先反向设计了服务器
is listening on a port and then we connected to it with netcat.
This video we want to go one layer deeper and have a look at the TCP protocol.
这将是我们第一次看到发送数据包意味着什么
the network.
We have used netcat now multiple times.
We used it in CTFs and last video to connect to challenges.
And in the web security series we used it to talk to a real webserver.
So you know that netcat is a very handy tool to send tcp packets over the network.
So I suggest we download wireshark to analyse packets we send with netcat.
When we open wireshark we select the network interface we want to capture packets.
In this case our traffic doesn’t leave the machine thus we can select the loopback interface.
环回更像是一个虚拟的网络接口，它不是一个真正的物理网卡卡住了
in your PC.
Through this interface will go all our traffic that we send around on our local machine.
And as you may know, the own machine is always identified as localhost or IP 127.0.0.1.
现在让我们使用两个终端窗口，在一个窗口中，我们以监听模式启动netcat。
and we select a port.
在另一个窗口中，我们可以执行netstat，就像在最后一个视频中一样，我们可以列出所有
processes that are currently listening on a port.
And here is our netcat process.
你知道吗，让我们用strace来执行netcat服务器，这样我们就可以看到
syscalls that netcat uses to establish a server.
所以它将首先创建一个套接字，设置一些选项，然后绑定端口1234，现在正在监听
on that port and is now waiting for a connection to be established with accept.
It’s basically exactly what we reverse engineered in last video.
我们也可以快速检查wireshark，我们看不到任何数据包通过
network yet.
Ok.
Now let’s use the second window to connect to this netcat server.
您可以在服务器上看到accept现在返回，因为客户端与
port.
And now, we see three entries in wireshark.
We see a SYN, SYNACK and ACK. packet.
Let’s quickly have a look at those.
As you can see in the lowest window, a packet is just some binary data.
And that binary data has meaning which wireshark can parse and display us nicely.
So above it we can see the decoded packet and it’s divided by layers.
Because this packet didn’t leave our machine the ethernet layer is just all zeroes.
Usually you would find here your mac address and the mac address from your switch or router.
So that layer is only used between two direct connections.
Besides the Mac addresses, this layer also contains a TYPE.
And the type is set to hex 800, which indicates that the next layer is an IPv4 layer.
Wireshark sees that and knows now how to decode the next bytes.
单击下一层时，wireshark将突出显示包的哪些字节属于
to that layer.
然后您可以看到它是如何决定它是一个IPv4，版本4层的，因为
first 4 bits of this byte is 4.
You can also see here the source and destination IP, which in this case is the same.
因此，当带有MAC地址的以太网层是关于直接连接时，IP层
在互联网上可以包含一个非常远的地址，并且交换机将确保
that this packet is forwarded until you reach that machine.
这个层还包含了关于层的信息，这就是协议
identifier.
In this case it’s 6, which means the content of this IP layer is a TCP header.
IP和TCP通常在一起，这很常见，因此您可能听说过
of TCP/IP before, which just says that there is a TCP layer over an IP layer.
因此，以太网层有助于从一台机器到另一台机器，IP层有助于识别
TCP层现在将帮助识别
program or process on this machine should handle this packet.
And that is identified with the port number.
You can see here that the destination port is set to 1234.
您还可以在这里看到一个源端口，这是必需的，这样您就可以从
this server.
所以当服务器用一个包响应时，它将使用这个端口，这样客户端
machine knows which process gets this response.
And that’s usually a random high port number.
不管怎样，现在我们了解了完整的TCP包是如何构造的，现在让我们来看看
the protocol.
A Protocol just refers to a set of rules on how to talk to another computer.
If a client and server agree on how to send data back and forth, it will work.
So What we will see now is just what somebody came up with in order to create a data connection.
请记住，目前我们还没有向netcat发送任何数据，到目前为止，我们只建立了
a connection.
Ok, so we see that 3 packets were exchanged.
First the client sent a so called SYN packet, a synchronize packet.
And then the server responded with an SYN,ACK packet.
Meaning I acknowledge that I received it.
This is important because maybe the initial packet didn’t arrive.
So when you as a client get a response, you know that the server got your message.
This means the client knows now that the connection works.
但是从服务器的角度来看，服务器还不知道发送
packet was successful.
Maybe the server can only receive but not send packets.
因此，客户机将用一个ACK包响应SYN、ACK包，确认
它得到了服务器的回答，现在双方都确定，是的，我成功地交换了数据包
with this other machine, now we can talk data.
And this is all done transparently.
You didn’t have to construct these packets yourself.
You simply opened a socket and waited for a connection.
Ok.
Now let’s send some data from the client to the server.
You can see that immediately the server was able to read the line you sent.
How does that look in wireshark.
We see two new packets.
A PSH packet from the client to the server, and an ack packet back.
The packet from the client also now has an additional DATA layer.
And that data layer just contains the raw bytes we sent.
服务器用ACK响应，通知客户端包成功
received.
Now let’s send a response from the server.
你看，服务器只是把文本写到文件描述符4，它是文件描述符
that accept returned.
如您所见，应用程序只需写入该paseudo文件、该套接字和
magic below sent that over the network.
现在让我们看看它做了什么，它还发送了一个psh包和客户机
acknwoledged the arrival with an ack packet back.
One more more thing.
Obviously the size of a packet is limited.
所以当你发送大量数据时会发生什么，比如说你上传了一个巨大的文件，
那怎么办？
Let’s just copy a bunch of characters and send them.
Ahhh, see, now there are more than just two packets.
在开发应用程序时，您不会看到它，但在内核、网卡或
driver, I don’t really know, it got split up.
您还可以看到第二个包没有与第一个包一起发送，第二个包
packet was only sent out once the server acknowledges the first one.
Let’s see what happens when you kill the client.
即使我们只是ctrl+c netcat，我们也可以在wireshark中看到，fin包已经发送了
out, do indicate we are done with this channel.
You can free up your resources and you don’t have to expect more packets from this connection.
And like during setup, there are 3 packets exchanged.
服务器通过客户机确认fin，现在客户机知道，服务器知道
that it is done.
但是服务器还不知道客户机是否知道它已经完成了，所以它也
responds with an ack.
Now both now that it’s over.
Now this whole exchange is referred to as a TCP stream.
We established a connection, then exchanged data back and forth, and then quit the connection.
And wireshark allows us to investigate this stream, for example with Follow TCP stream.
Here only the data is visible and color coded who sent what.
现在您应该从Web安全系列中观看我的HTTP协议视频，因为
you will understand now much better what it means to have a server and client.
And that HTTP is just data sent over TCP, exactly how we sent these messages.
浏览器和Web服务器只是一些特殊的程序，它们用特殊的
messages received over TCP.